

Debashish Sahu

Senior Interaction Designer, 3 Years (Design) & 3.5 Years (Development)

Sr. Interaction Designer, Imaginea Design Labs

As a Sr. Interaction Designer, a major portion of my work involves coming up with new and best experiences for the varied software or digital products in the Design Labs and leading from the front.

Following are brief list of key responsibilities:

- Lead brainstorming and conceptualization sessions internally as well as the clients; elicit and evolve the business requirements through interviews and workshops.
- Work within multi-disciplinary teams to ideate on design challenges as well as to evaluate the feasibility of proposed solutions.
- · Develop use cases, personas, scenarios and storyboards.
- · Define user task and interaction flows.
- Create screen-level interaction designs and detailed user interface specifications.

Also working and heading the IoT Lab within the design team. The IoT Lab is not only centered around IoT but extends to the field of Tangible Media where we find ways to deliver experience across channel with the help of the latest technologies.

Personal Information

Date of Birth

December 19th, 1982

Address

6-3-628/7, Ravindra Nagar Anand Nagar Colony, Khairatabad Hyderabad-500004

Email

debashishsahu@outlook.com

Phone

+91-7406891234

Employment

2015 - Current

Senior Interaction Designer @ Pramati Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

from December, 2015 to Current

Sr. Designer & Design Lead in Imaginea Design Labs

As a Sr. Interaction Designer, a major portion of my work involves coming up with new and best experiences for the varied software or digital products in the Design Labs and leading from the front.

Following are some of the design projects executed by me:

- FlyDubai Holidays, FlyDubai
 User Research Analyst User Personas Usability Testing
- Microclear, Agility Logistics Web | Resp. App Requirement Analysis & Scoping Wireframes
- Hyderabad Metro, Fission Labs Mobile App
 Requirement Gathering & Scoping Usecase Detailing Wireframes
- <u>Ezili App and Retail Concepts, In-House</u>
 User Research Market Research Brainstorming Conceptualization Persona Creation Usecase Detailing
 Wireframes Visual Design
- Spine Chair, In-House
 User Research Feasibility Study Wireframes H/W Prototyping

2013 - 2015

User Experience Designer @ Mindtree Ltd.

from November, 2013 to December, 2015

Worked as Interaction Designer/User Experience Designer in a co-innovation lab called The Digital Pumpkin.

The Digital Pumpkin was a CoE of the upcoming technology be it Tangible Media, IoT, gestures based devices, AR/VR etc. the idea was to create a working showcase of products and solutions which could link experience, end-users and business together.

Majorly worked on interaction and UX of all the PoC & prototypes which were built under the banner.

The work was usually spanned across different facets of the Design Process be it User Research, Competitor Analysis, Technical Feasibility, Feature Analysis, Product Design etc. <u>Portfolio Link</u>

2010 - 2011

Senior Software Engineer, MDG @ Nagarro Softwares & Pvt. Ltd.

from August, 2010 to April, 2011

Design and Development of Sharepoint Web Portals

Worked as a Senior Software Engineer, Member Delivery Group in developing Web based applications in Microsoft Technologies in MOSS 2007 and SharePoint Server 2010. The task mainly involved customization of master pages, design and development of custom webparts, site templates, page templates etc.

Following were the intranet and internet webportals which I worked on:

- Estee Lauder Web Portal, Estee Lauder Inc. [Jan/2011 Apr/2011]
- TAIT Web Portal, TAIT Inc. [Oct/2010 Dec/2010]
- e-Health Solutions, Sigmacare & Co. Inc. [Jul/2010 Sep/2010]

2007 - 2010

Software Engineer @ L&T Infotech

from November, 2008 to April, 2010

Design and Development of Sharepoint Web Portals

Worked as a Software Engineer in the Team which worked exclusively on the various internet and intranet webportals for Viacom Inc.

Following were the projects which I worked on:

- International Portals, Viacom Inc. [Feb/2010 Mar/2010]
- CSD-EM, Viacom Inc. [Oct/2008 Feb/2010]
- Viacom MS Portal Support, Viacom Inc. [Aug/2008 to Oct/2008]
- NickPress, Viacom Inc. [Apr/2008 to Aug/2008]

Education

2011 - 2013

PGDPD, New Media Design

from 2011 to 2013

National Institute of Design

The New Media Design Programme is trans-disciplinary in nature, applying and integrating knowledge from various disciplines. In this sense, it is a unique combination of design, art, science and technology.

2003 - 2007

B.E. Computer Science

from 2003 to 2007

Lingaya's Institute of Mgmt. and Technology

Completed B.E., Computer Science from Lingaya's Institute of Technology affiliated to Maharishi Dayanand University, Rohtak.

2002 - 2003

Advanced Diploma in Software Technology

from 2002 to 2003

ECIT

Successfully completed Advance Diploma in Software Technology from ECIT (Govt. of India undertaking institute)

Skills

Design

User Experience Design, Interaction Design, User Personas, Storyboards, Wireframes

Tools

Adobe Illustrator

Expert

Adobe Photoshop

Good

Sketch

Expert

Indesign

Very Good

Adobe Fireworks

Very Good

Balsamiq Expert

Axure RP

Good

Unity 3D Average

Development

Scripting Languages HTML, CSS, javaScript, jQuery, XML

Programming

Languages C, C++, C#, Java, Python, VB

Hobbies

Movies , Singing , Bicycling , Computer Games , Creative Coding , Reading , Traveling, Cooking